

# Ismail Ahmed Abu-Absah

Phone No (M) +966- 533 26 26 29 E-mail: <u>ism000sa@yahoo.com</u>



## **Personal Information**

Nationality: Palestinian

Date of birth: 20/10/1980

Marital Status: Married

# **Career Objective**

To contribute towards the growth and development of a dynamic Organization that offers learning opportunities in a competitive environment and appreciates the performance criterion, of technical growth.

# **Profile**

**20+ (21)** years of experience in the field of networking and Security, which involved to develop and articulate the information management strategy and framework based on business strategy; ensure that the appropriate framework, standards, tools and technologies are implemented and maintained; guide organization information governance activities; and plan and apply processes, policies and projects to capture, control, protect and deliver the value of both data and information as an organizational asset.

Implement organization solution on-premise and on the cloud according to the internal standards and procedures and operate them in line with the agreed SLAs and KPIs from provisioning to administering, operating, monitoring, and supporting to meet the requirements of internal and external business stakeholders, ensure availability and performance.

Performs and manages technical and analytical work in the design, planning, implementation, and management of information security related infrastructure. Provide a secure computing environment for the organization by developing and implementing comprehensive information security program including implementation of standard Information Security policies and procedures.

### **Education:**

Bachelor of Science Business Administration 2016 - 2020 Diploma in Computer Hardware & Network. 2000-2002

## **Professional Certification:**

CCIE (Cisco Certified Internetwork Expert). CCIE#37063

**CCNP** (Cisco Certified Network Professional).

**CCVP** (Cisco Certified Voice Professional).

**CCSP** (Cisco Certified Security Professional).

**MCSE** (Microsoft Certified System Engineer).

Microsoft Certified Professional - MCP.

Cisco Securing Networks with PIX and ASA.

Cisco Information Security Specialist.

Cisco Firewall Specialist.

Cisco ASA VPN Solutions.

Cisco Intrusion Prevention System IPS Specialist.

Cisco Implementing Intrusion Prevention Systems.

Cisco Implementing Network Admission Control NAC Appliance.

Cisco Network Admission Control Specialist.

Cisco Securing Network Devices.

Cisco Securing Network with Routers and Switches.

CCNSP (Cyberoam Certified Network & Security Professional).

KasperSky Anti-Virus for Windows Workstations and Windows File Servers.

McAfee Network Security Platform Administration.

Cisco Building Cisco Remote Access Networks BCRAN.

Cisco Building Multilayer Switched Networks.

Cisco Building Scalable Internetworks.

Cisco Optimizing Converged Networks.

Cisco Quality of Service.

Cisco Troubleshooting Unified Communications.

Cisco Unified Communications IP Telephony Part.

Cisco Voice Over IP.

Cisco CCNA 1 Networking Basics.

Cisco CCNA 2 Routers and Routing Basics.

Cisco CCNA 3 Switching Basics and Intermediate Routing.

Cisco CCNA 4 WAN Technologies.

Microsoft Designing Windows Directory Services Infrastructure.

Microsoft Implementing Microsoft Windows Server & Professional.

Microsoft Implementing and Administering a Windows Directory Services Infrastructure.

Microsoft Implementing and Administering a Windows Network Infrastructure.

Microsoft Implementing and Administering Windows Directory Services.

Microsoft Implementing Windows Server Network Infrastructure.

Microsoft Installing, Configuring, and Administering Exchange Server.

Microsoft Installing, Configuring, and Administering Internet Security and Acceleration ISA Server.

Microsoft Installing, Configuring, and Administering Windows Professional.

Microsoft Installing, Configuring, and Administering Windows Server.

Lync 2010 Deployment.

HP Matrix Operating Environment Infrastructure Admin.

General English Course Level 3.

General English Upper-Intermediate Level 2.

Business English Course with British Council.

Business Writing Skills.

Intro to MS Project Workshop.

PMP Project Management Professional Exam Prep Workshop.

Practical Intro to PM Project Management Workshop.

Applied Project Management Workshop.

The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People.

#### **Professional Work Experience:**

**Senior Network Engineer & Team Leader**— Network Department **June 2009 – 2020** *Abdul Latif Jameel Co. (Toyota) – IT Division* 

Responsible for planning and designing network structure growth throughout the kingdom, as well as leading the operational team through day-to-day activities in all aspects of wireless, voice, security, routing and switching operations.

# **Senior Network Engineer** – Network Department

Jan 2007- June 2009

AlMutlag United Company

Team leader, responsible for providing networking solutions to clients in all fields of wireless, voice, security, routing & switching.

#### **Senior Network Engineer** – Network Department

Jan 2003- Jan 2007

Jeraisy Computer Communication Services

Senior engineer of the technical operations teams responsible for all new installations and troubleshooting of routing & switching and wireless.

#### **Network Engineer** – Network Department

Apr 2000- Jan 2003

Saudi German Hospital Group

Responsible for the administration of the group network and providing technical support on daily operations.

#### **Assistant Network Engineer** – Network Department

Feb 1998- Apr 2000

AlAtlal Center

Part time junior network engineer responsible for technical support and daily operations.

#### **Responsibilities & Skills**

- Team leading and management experience.
- Worked under various circumstances in LAN and WAN network.
- Building, maintaining and troubleshooting complex networks.
- Protection of networks against internal and external malicious treats.
- Configuring, maintaining and troubleshooting the routers, switches and servers.
- Configuring, maintaining and troubleshooting the Wireless Networks.
- Configuring, maintaining and troubleshooting the VoIP and IP telephony network.
- Highly adaptable to change and fluidity of the organizational needs to ensure team can perform under complex and uncertain environment and demands to achieve outcomes.
- Knowledge and experience in enterprise-level solution integration.
- Formulate and review plans for both current and future strategies for information security management and information technology goals, objectives, and programs. Implement adequate policies and procedures that guide the provision of secure IT services.
- Supervise development of Information Security Plans; and, evaluation, implementation and management of IT security solutions across the Group.
- Design and review the implementation of Information Security policies and procedures.
- Formulate and apply the security policies or initiatives to mitigate risks.
- Supervise the development, documentation, communication, testing, and periodic review and revision of business continuity and disaster recovery plans.
- Design, and implement Information Security service / operating level agreements with partners and suppliers. Manage security related risk in all IT projects.
- Review, analyze and resolve IT Security problems using vulnerability software's and technical troubleshooting processes and periodic security assessments.
- Supervise the user access to network/systems, applications and other IT infrastructure components as per the policy.
- Formulate and review the technical documentation of the IT Network Security Architecture and design and technically guide the implementation of controls, in current and new systems, to reduce risk to the business.
- Monitor and review the daily logs of Information Security services for IT Solutions, such as SWIFT, VPN, Anti-Virus and demonstrating improvement of service levels, in order to protect organization Group Systems and Information.
- Formulate daily, weekly and monthly security monitoring activities to verify the integrity and Security of the IT Infrastructure and resolve performance Security issues.
- Formulate RFI, RFQ, RFP documents related to IT Security solutions and contribute to the technical evaluation of vendor proposals and negotiation/finalization of vendor contracts.
- Manage all change and release management activities for the implementation of the network solution in the production environment.
- Periodically review reports on project status, including progress, issues and risks
- Participate in research and keep abreast of the developments in IT industry, and best practices for emerging enterprise server, storage and backup technologies and solutions.
- Design, prepare and deliver Risk Management framework and assisting the implementation of controls, in current and new systems, to reduce risk to clients and the business.